Operation Underground Battle
Wow!
It's a drone with a camera!
I got it yesterday.
With this, we can find the robot hiding in the forest from a safe distance.
Uh... about that robot...
You lost it, didn't you? I heard from Sebastian.
I'm... just so glad you're okay, Crest!
Yeah, we were so worried!
I think that forest is too dangerous. It's best we stay away from it from now on.
Yeah, I think so too.
But that robot said it hated humans. We can't just ignore it.
I wonder just how much Crest knows about the Metal Cardbots.
Uncle Edo!
The monster turned out to be a Metal Cardbot after all.
Let go of him!
Wait up, Crest!
He didn't seem surprised at all.
What was that?
Is that?...
Mega Ambler? What's going on?
Jun. It's an emergency.
A water main burst and water is gushing out.
The cause is unknown.
There's a sinkhole here too. I don't think I can handle this on my own!
Please send help!
Alright. I'll be there right away.
Huh?! What's that?!
Dexter?!
Who is it?!
So you've been causing these sinkholes all over town!
Shut up!
Got it. Over.
What's going on?!
It was Dexter.
Wasn't he trying to protect the animals?
Why did he come all the way to Mowtown?!
I think it might be trying to destroy the roads to protect the animals.
People aren't stopping the road construction despite all the warnings,
so it's trying to destroy all the roads for the animal's sake.
Wait, show us a map of the town!
These are the places that sinkholes appeared.
Let's connect them and see if we can figure something out.
Looks like there's no pattern.
Dexter's eyes were damaged when Wild Guardy attacked.
He probably doesn't even know where he's going.
Isn't that... all the more reason to destroy the robot?
So we can prevent it from causing any more damage?
He's not just a robot! He's a mechanical lifeform from planet Machina!
We should try our best to persuade to him!
Do you really think he'll listen?
Dexter's heart is in the right place for wanting to protect the animals.
He just chose the wrong way to go about it.
But what if we can't persuade him?
We'll stop him, even if it means fighting.
Whether you want to talk or fight, you have to find it first.
How will you find it when it's burrowed deep underground.
That's why I have a plan.
Operation Underground Battle!
Operation Underground Battle?
For this operation to succeed...
Crest. We'll need your help.
What is that on top of the drone?
It's an ultrasonic generator used to repel moles.
I got it because Jun said he needed one.
The drone will take this into one of the sinkholes.
Dexter is relying on sound to get around.
So this should get him to pop right up out of the ground!
Here's the map of the sewers! I got it from my dad.
Thank you!
But how will we be able to communicate with the drone while it's underground?
Worry not. Allow me to take care of that.
Sebastian?
I have memorized the map.
Thank you.
I'll be off then!
Let's get going too!
We have a signal on the radar.
Is it Dexter?
It's big...
It's coming!
It's just a rat...
How are things going out here?
Shall we try again?
Is that?...
There it is!
Wow...! A, uh, robot!
It looks dangerous, let's run!
W-wait up! But we finally found Dexter!
Huh? Is that the little human?
Yaah!
What the-? Make that awful noise stop already!
Dexter! We don't want to fight you!
We'll find a way to protect the animals!
So please stop attacking innocent people!
What? Humans protecting the animals?
Don't make me laugh!
Dexter! Listen to me!
Metal Cardbots have to learn to coexist with humans,
so we can live in peace on this planet together!
No! Humans can't be trusted!
Master of the Metal Breath! You're just lying so you can capture me too!
Uh-oh. If it can't be helped...
Then I'll have to do this! Shadow X!
Stealth mode, off!
Stop right there!
When did you...
We were prepared in case you wouldn't listen to us!
Haha!
He's been standing by since before we began this operation!
Looks like there will be a fight after all.
Jun... please take care of things here.
Huh?
Hey you! Let us seal you already!
Over my dead body!
He can use his shovel like that?!
Huh?
Tch. Where did he go?
Hiding is supposed to be my thing!
I can't use my main camera.
But my sound wave device can detect where you are!
There you are!
Hey! Let go!
Come back, Shadow X!
Your turn, Phoenix Fire!
Just try and follow me!
He went back underground!
Dexter is tracking our location through sound...
!
In that case.
Phoenix Fire! Hammer Quake!
Hammer...
Quake!
Augh!
Phoenix Fire! Keep hitting the ground!
Hammer Quake! And another!
Augh! Stop it!
Behind you!
Water Splash!
Augh!
Way to go!
Your up, Mega Ambler!
Mega Ambler! Stop him from going back underground!
Got it. Leave it to me!
Forceps Crush!
Let go of me!
Oh no!
Great job, guys!
Metal Breath, pickup!
Blue Cop, setup!
Dexter! It's time to settle this!
You!
Blue Cop!
Infinity...
Force...
Break!!
Metal Cardbot...
Change Up!
Dexter-
Sealed!
Now, what do you see?
What?
A gorilla waving?
Looks like he's been fixed!
What do you mean by that?
Thank you guys.
I really owe you an apology.
Hey, don't worry about it.
If there's anything on your mind, you can tell us.
You guys were able to help me...
But what will happen to the animals of the forest when the road is finished?
!
I have something to show you. Come with me!
We're here!
What?
This underpass has been designed to allow wild animals to cross safely, Dexter.
Humans also thought of a way to keep the wild animals safe.
I see the people of this planet have shown a little consideration after all.
Do you feel better now?
Yeah. From now on...
I will join you as a part of your team.
Haha! Glad to have you!